ASHEQ IMRAN

Software Developer in San Francisco Bay Area

(703) 870-9809 📞

asheq89@gmail.com

asheqimran in





SUMMARY

Programmer with a love for writing high-performing software that is both useful and easy to use. Extensive professional experience in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, AngularJS, Google Polymer, and MATLAB. Currently building the front-end for gas turbine edge applications. Background in systems and controls theory, and interested in applied math and science.



EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Aug 2012 – Aug 2013

M.S. in Electrical & Computer Engineering | Specialty in Systems & Controls

Relevant Courses: Autonomous Control of Robotic Systems, Digital Control, Dynamics and Control of Hybrid Electric Vehicles, Nonlinear Systems, Satellite Communication & Navigation Systems, Computer Vision

Georgia Institute of Technology

Aug 2007 – May 2012

B.S. in Electrical & Computer Engineering | *Summa cum laude*



EXPERIENCE

General Electric | Software Developer

Aug 2013 - Present

- Wrote front-end code for gas turbine advisory applications that help electric utilities maximize profits.
- Wrote idiomatic JavaScript for web apps using prototype-based inheritance, events, and promises.
- Utilized functional programming concepts by writing pure functions and pushing DOM mutations to the edge.
- Completed Edison Engineering Development Program (EEDP). Wrote code for iPad apps using PhoneGap in JavaScript/HTML/CSS, firmware for smart meters in C, and Zigbee network packet dissectors in Lua.

Broadcom | Graduate Intern

Jan 2013 – May 2013

• Tested SOCs used in consumer electronics. Automated test procedures using programmable multi-channel DMMs.

SAIC | Intern

May 2011 – Aug 2012

• Developed geospatial software that processes photographs taken from satellites and aircrafts for a DARPA project.



SKILLS

- JavaScript
- D3.js ESLint
- HTML
- CSS
- Git • TDD
- MATLAB AngularJS

Polymer

- i18n & l10n
- UX Principles
- Web Components
- UML Diagrams
- WebSockets
- Regular Expressions
- Wireframing with Sketch
- RESTful API Design in OpenAPI
- Debugging with Chrome DevTools
- Build Automation with Gulp
- Unix Tools and Bash Shell
- OO Design Patterns



INTERESTS

User Experience, Graphics & Visualization, Artificial Intelligence, Computational Physics, Systems Integration



AWARDS

- GE Digital App-a-thon Winner | 2016
- CST Engineering Award for Outstanding Technology Achievement | 2016
- Controls Symposium Predix App Contest Winner | 2015 & 2016